

Fabian Andres ALVAREZ HOYOS

Age: 33 años Calle 62n # 2bn-77, Cali-Colombia **Mobile:**3162895888

E-mail: atlon_999@hotmail.com, falvarezh87@gmail.com **Linkedin:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/fabian-andres-alvarez-hoyos-b4991276/

I'm passionate about development, constantly learning new technologies. I have worked on software development projects for the financial and industrial (productive) sector.

Designed Public, Private and Hybrid Cloud solutions with add-on managed services for Enterprise clients in Colombia, United States and Spain

Experience in WebSphere Message Broker, IIB, C#.NET, Oracle, Angular7+, Javascript, Node, Java, Microservices, Jenkins, Docker, Net Core, VueJs, ReacJs, AWS, Azure

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Year 2008 Degree System Technologist

Cali-Colombia Centro Colombiano de Estudios Profesionales

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

English: Intermediate.

WORK EXPERIENCE

From 01/10/2021 - Present Medellín-Colombia) CEIBA SOFTWARE, Sector Tecnology

Position : Technical Coach

Technical Coach, in charge of designing a cloud-native platform for a United States client in the insurance sector, Deployed in AWS and additionally in charge of developing multiple functionalities in new and existing platforms **USED TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS:** Enterprise Architect 10.0, DrawlO, AWS Architecture. **Development:** Java Spring, Java Spring Security, Java Hibernate, Java JPA, Azure Devops, AWS Lambda (Java and JavaScript), Docker, VueJS, NodeJs Nest, NodeJs Express, ReactJs

From 13/10/2020 to 30/09/2021 Medellín-Colombia)

PERSONALSOFT, Sector Tecnology

Position : Solutions Architect

Outsourcing (On Site) in Bancolombia in charge of designing the architecture of the solution for 2 projects in Azure. View, Functional and Physical Diagrams.

USED TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS: Enterprise Architect 10.0, Architecture SOAP, AWS Architecture. **Development:** Java Spring, Java Spring Security, Java Hibernate, Java JPA, Azure Devops, AWS Lambda (Java and JavaScript), Docker, VueJS

From 18/02/2020 to 18/09/2020 Cali-Colombia) MANAWA CONSULTING, Sector Tecnology

Position : Solutions Architect

Design and development of backend architecture (Microservices) for a billing project for a leading business group in Spain, the technologies used are Java Spring, Netflix Zuul, Netflix Eureka Server with Oracle 19g database All microservices are deployed in Docker containers automatically with Jenkins Pro.

USED TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS: Enterprise Architect 10.0, Arquitectura Microservicios, Java Spring, Java Spring Security, Eureka Server, Netflix Zuul, Docker, Jenkins, Oracle 19g, Nexus, Maven, VueJS

From 13/05/2019 to 13/03/2020 Medellín-Colombia)

PERSONALSOFT, Sector Tecnology

Position : Solutions Architect

Outsourcing (On Site) in Bancolombia in charge of designing the architecture of the solution for 2 projects in Azure. View, Functional and Physical Diagrams.

USED TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS: Enterprise Architect 10.0, Architecture SOAP, AWS Architecture. **Development:** Java Spring, Java Spring Security, Java Hibernate, Java JPA, Azure Devops, AWS Lambda (Java and JavaScript), Docker.

From 01/03/2017 to 10/05/2019 Cali-Colombia)

ARKAN GROUP, Sector Tecnology

Position : Solutions Architect

I'm in charge of planning in detail how the different solutions will be implemented. Design of SOAP integration services. Architecture design of the different client-type applications (MVC-WebApi .Net). Estimation of effort necessary to carry out the developments. Definition of appropriate technologies to propose solutions to customers. Responsible for analyzing the needs of customers. Design of activity diagrams for the subsequent development of services.

USED TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS: WPF (MVC), WebApi (.Net), Javascript, Java, Angular, IBM Message Broker V8.0, IBM ILOG V8.0, Oracle 11G (RDBMS) PL / SQL, SQLServer 2014, Enterprise Architect 10.0, Architecture SOAP, Java Spring, Java Spring Security, Java Hibernate, Java JPA, Docker.

From 01/11/2015 to 28/02/2017 Cali-Colombia)

DIGITAL CONSULTING GROUP, Sector

Tecnology Position: Project Engineer

Outsorcing (On Site) in a company of the financial sector. Lead different work teams, to distribute and tackle the tasks assigned in the PMO area. Plan and control the tasks of the development engineers. Support all developments in different environments (Java, .NET). Development of services with SOAP architecture in IBM Websphere Message Broker. Definition scheme

development of the WPF C # client applications (.Net-MVC). As well as the development of all the necessary utilities for the integration with the services.

USED TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS: WPF (MVC), WebApi (.Net), Javascript, IBM Message Broker V8.0, IBM ILOG V8.0, Oracle 11G (RDBMS) PL/SQL, SQLServer 2014, Java Spring, Java Spring Security, Java Hibernate, Java JPA, Docker

From 01/01/2015 to 31/10/2015 Cali-Colombia)

PROALNET, Sector Tecnology

Position : Software Development Manager

Establish a strategic plan for the start and development of the systems to be designed. Analyze workloads of the staff, establishing necessary balances. Follow up on the tasks assigned to the staff to avoid delays in the established schedules. Coordinate meetings with developers in order to verify progress and possible problems in the tasks.

USED TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS: ASP.NET, KendoJS, AngularJS, MVC Razor, WebAPI, ODATA Rest, OAuth, Entity Framework, WCF, SQL Server 2008 - 2012.

From 06/02/2014 to 31/12/2014 Cali-Colombia)

PROALNET, Sector Tecnology

Position : Software Developer

Web Developer C # and SQL Server 2008 R2. MVC Razor. Kendo Javascript. JQuery WebApi (REST), AngularJS. In charge of creating services for the interface with clients' ERP (SAP, ORACLE ...). In charge of developing WebServices for client ERP interface.

LABOR REFERENCES

Jose OSPINA

PROALNET (Cali-Colombia) CEO Mobile 3188278905 Email aladino.ospina@proalnet.com

Eric LAM

Mulu Inc (San Francisco-USA) CTO Mobile 3165394906 Email elam044@hotmail.com

PERSONAL REFERENCES

Andrea CASTILLO Wife (Cali-Colombia)

Independiente Mobile: 3186043576

Email: andreca423@gmail.com

Yorleider CASTILLO Brother in law (Cali-Colombia)

Student

Mobile 3158490096

Email: grone0919@gmail.com

ADDITIONAL TRAINING AND INTERESTS

WM666G-IBM Integration Bus V10 Application Development I, Master Docker with Java - DevOps for Spring Microservices Angular 7: Creando web app full-stack con Spring Framework 5 Programación Reactiva con Spring Boot 2 y Spring WebFlux Curso de Angular 7 avanzado: MEAN, JWT, Módulos, Animaciones Desarrollo web con Spring Boot 2 & Spring Framework 5 Jenkins Curso Intensivo para DevOps y Desarrolladores.

Sports Hobbies: Futbol